# Cihan CINAR

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - FULLSTACK

# **PROFILE**

I am a Full Stack Software Engineer, with over 5 years of experience and always eager to learn something new.

I am also part of the Worldline Expert Community and am recognized as a Technical Expert.

I am currently employed at Atos Worldline on OpenBanking issues, where I am working in agile methodology on various projects, with high expectations and tight deadlines. Specialized in Java, I am actively working on software design, architecture and IaaS, CaaS deployment. However I am adaptable and I enjoy learning new technologies.

Pedagogue and passionate about my work, I participate in university or inhouse technical trainings. I actively follow web conferences such as Devoxx to keep me informed of the latest technologies and trends and I try to implement new approaches that I think are promising. The technical challenge is at the heart of

# **EXPERIENCE**

# equensWorldline

## Senior Software Engineer - OpenBanking

#### 🗐 06/2020 - Present

Design and development of a generic consent, authorization and authentication solution using the OPENID connect protocol through RH SSO and Apigee. I build the architecture of the identity provider platform for the largest English bank.

I am working with our TPP Reach solutions to design and respond to pre-sales, and I'm studying the implementation of a solution like Google login for banks.

I am working on the design of a green banking solution with the implementation of carbon footprint calculation for banking transactions.

Keycloak, Apigee, Drupal

Java 11, SpringBoot (Security, MVC, Data, WebFlux), Maven, Angular 9, Openshift, Helm, Gitlab-ci, Docker, Jira

## **Senior Software Engineer - Chatbot**

#### **🗎** 09/2019 - 06/2020

Design and development of a chatbot solution using channels such as Alexa, Google Home, Messenger, Rest API, WebSocket, using for intention recognition our RASA-based NLP engine coupled with an approaching search and disambiguation engine.

Implementation of an administration tool for corpus management and administration of the bot and discussions on the different channels.

Kotlin, SpringBoot (Security, MVC, Data), Maven, Angular 9, Openshift, Helm, Gitlab-ci, Docker, Jira

# **Software Engineer - PSD2**

# **10/2018 - 09/2019**

Design, development and operation of the Digital Banking product line for the implementation of the PSD2 standard based on the BerlinGroup and OpenBanking standards, through the Apigee API manager. I carried out the performance tests as well as the patches. I set up the whole DevOps part. And I lead technically a team of 10 developers.

Java, SpringBoot (Cloud, Security, Data, MVC), Docker, Ember, Kafka, Drupal, Maven, Node, TI S

# **Software Engineer - Digital Signature**

#### **3**03/2016 - 10/2018

- Design, development and operation of underwriting applications of dematerialized contracts for various banking and insurance customers, implementing the electronic signature.

Java, SpringBoot (XML, Boot, MVC, Data), AngularJs, REST et SOAP, Maven, TLS

- Design, development and operation of a digital banking product for the implementation of API connector between third parties and bank for all banking transactions.

Java, JEE, Spring (Cloud), Ember, REST, Maven, Node, TLS

#### CONTACT

- **\** +33 6 43 27 96 40
- □ cihancnr@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/cihancinar
- github.com/cihancinar
- O cihancinar.github.io/
- ◆ 5 Allee des Platanes, Venissieux 69200 FRANCE

# LANGUAGE

English

French

Turkish

# LAST TRAINING

- Kafka Developer Skils
- Blockchain
- Openshift
- Kotlin
- Docker

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Université Claude Bernard Lyon 1

#### Part-time teacher

**1**0/2018 - 12/2018 & **1**0/2019 - 12/2019

Teacher (practical work) for web application design courses for 1st year of master computer science of the university Lyon 1.

The general theme is "web-oriented" design using software engineering patterns (MVC, REST, asynchronous, framework, templating.). Technically, it involves programming in Java on the server side (servlet, JSP, Spring) and in JS on the client side (AJAX, jQuery).

# LIRIS - CNRS (Research Laboratory in computer science)

#### Internship

**6** 05/2015 - 08/2015

Development of a graph storage engine for a distributed system.

Multi-segment partition loading, latices generation, compression and code optimization with float loading.

Work on the Petasky project, on the fragmentation and data storage part, in C++, JAVA, SPARQL and RDF.

## **EDUCATION**

Université Claude Bernard Lyon 1 9 France, Lyon

## Master of Information Technology and Web in Computer Science

**2014 - 2016** 

IUT Informatique Dijon ♥ France, Dijon

## **University of Computer Science**

**2011 – 2013** 

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

# **Programmation:**

# Software Development:

Java 11, Kotlin, JEE, Spring (Cloud, Boot, MVC, Data, Security), Docker, Node.JS *Web Development:* 

HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript (Angular 9, EmberJS), jQuery

#### **Continus integration:**

Jenkins, Gitlab (CI), HELM

#### **Project management:**

Agile (Scrum), Jira

# **Database Technologies:**

SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

#### **Tools:**

Keycloak, Apigee, Kafka, ELK